<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matt Johnson</title>
    <link>http://onlymattjohnson.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Matt Johnson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 15:22:25 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://onlymattjohnson.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Oh My Cron</title>
      <link>http://onlymattjohnson.com/2023/07/18/oh-my-cron/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 15:22:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://onlymattjohnson.com/2023/07/18/oh-my-cron/</guid>
      <description>Oh boy. I feel like I may never truly understand how cron works compared to other task scheduling applications. Today I went through a whole mess of steps to try and get a job scheduled to automatically generate my github contributions chart.
What happened? So, I was able to use the lovely githubchart gem to generate my githubchart SVG with no issues at all. It was so simple.
&amp;gt; gem install githubchart &amp;gt; githubchart -u onlymattjohnson .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Data Metrics</title>
      <link>http://onlymattjohnson.com/data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 14:50:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://onlymattjohnson.com/data/</guid>
      <description>This page holds a variety of personal data metrics that I&amp;rsquo;m interested in tracking. I think this may be where Hugo becomes a little tricky for me, but so far it is working for what I need.
Github A summary of github contributions that I&amp;rsquo;ve made. This chart is generated with the very helpful ruby gem githubchart by Les Aker. I used to use the rshah API to generate these but it stopped working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning About Linux Permissions</title>
      <link>http://onlymattjohnson.com/2023/02/03/learning-about-linux-permissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 11:56:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://onlymattjohnson.com/2023/02/03/learning-about-linux-permissions/</guid>
      <description>So, who knows what&amp;rsquo;s a good pace for writing blog posts, but since I&amp;rsquo;m in the habit of writing up notes about new things I learn, might as well write a post even though I already put one up earlier today.
Permissions So, I&amp;rsquo;ve got this website running on a linux server which serves this out of a directory /var/www/onlymattjohnson.com which is owned by the www-data group. I was trying to upload the files by ftp for my user but I found that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t write to the folder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A First Post</title>
      <link>http://onlymattjohnson.com/2023/02/03/a-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 11:32:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://onlymattjohnson.com/2023/02/03/a-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Hello! Welcome to my new website. This is a first post for my updated site that I would like to begin blogging on. The site is built with Hugo using a modificatio of the Archie theme
I will be making small tweaks here and there and figuring out how to automatically deploy this to my server, but first thing is first and I&amp;rsquo;m getting the site up and running. This is a first post to allow for that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh, hello there. I&#39;m Matt 👋</title>
      <link>http://onlymattjohnson.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 11:12:22 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://onlymattjohnson.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I’ve spent the better part of the last 17 years gathering, cleaning, and transforming data to find meaning and to move organizations forward. I’ve worked for non-profits, labor unions, governments, and a few universities.
Most days, I am writing SQL, building data pipelines, and modeling data. I find problems and I fix problems. Once the problems are fixed, I build reports to provide usable information to my colleagues.
I was born and raised in Chicago, but I currently live in the northwest suburbs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
